Jorge Muñoz

Email: jorgemf@gmail.com Personal web: https://jorgemf.github.io

Phone: (+34) 657 139 626 GitHub profile: https://github.com/jorgemf

Personal statement

I am a Deep Learning Researcher & Engineer. I have been working with Artificial Intelligence since I discovered it in the year 2000. In the last years, I have been working as a remote Deep Learning Researcher & Engineer for different startups of San Francisco, London and Madrid. I have even founded a startup with 2 colleagues where we did consultancy projects in Artificial Intelligence. I have an MBA and I have also pursued a Ph.D. in Artificial Intelligence before. I was graduated with first-class honors and I have been awarded several by the research and work done, both locally and internationally. I love maths since I was very young and I have been a finalist in a couple of international math contests I joined in as a hobby.

I want to focus my career in Deep Learning applied to products for final customers while I keep learning and doing research in the area. And also fulfill my goals in life which are being happy, unveil the secrets of the human mind and create Artificial Intelligence thanks to maths.

Education

October 2011 – November 2012	MBA Part-Time at EOI (Escuela de Organización Industrial) Management School. Funded by EOI (see awards and prizes below). International stay at UCF for a week.
October 2008 – October 2011	Ph.D. in Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence . Imitation learning in video games and the development of believable non-players characters. The main author of several published papers in international congress about computational intelligence in games (CIG 2009, CIG 2010, UKCI 2010).
October 2007 – September 2008	Master in Computer Science and Information Technology. Specialization: Artificial Intelligence . University Carlos III of Madrid. Funded by the university.
October 2001 – November 2006	Computer Science Engineering (5 years career). Specialization: Artificial Intelligence. Graduated with first-class honors and the best bachelor's thesis . University Carlos III of Madrid.

Experience

May 2018 – January 2020	Founder at Serendeepia (Madrid) Serendeepia Research is a small group of experts in Machine Learning and Deep Learning. We built custom solutions based on state of the art research and we helped our customers to develop their own capability to use Artificial Intelligence. I assumed the role of CEO and CTO of the company while I was helping with the projects we had.
January 2016 – August 2018	Remote Machine Learning Engineer/Researcher at Chute (San Francisco, CA, USA).
	I was the only one in charge of processing the data from social networks (Instagram, Twitter) in real-time to create valuable insights. Chute was acquired in August 2018.

Relevant projects:

- Multilabel image classification with **TensorFlow** and **TensorFlow Serving** (previously image classification with Caffe) in Python
- Aesthetic model to score the beautifulness of the images in TensorFlow
- Model in TensorFlow to create a perceptual hash of images using local and semantic information of images
- Library in Python to train, test and deploy TensorFlow and Caffe models
- Spam filter and user topics detection with Word2Vec and kmeans in Go
- Webapp in Ruby on Rails to organize the data for the image classification

June 2017 – April 2018

Remote contractor as Machine Learning Researcher at Good AI Lab (San Jose, CA, USA).

I was in charge to create **Deep Learning** research projects that run in ClusterOne for promoting and testing the platform. For example:

https://medium.com/clusterone/personalized-medicine-redefining-cancer-treatment-with-deep-learning-f6c64a366fff

March 2013 – September 2017

Android lead developer in startups in London (Quipper, Shopcade) and as a remote contractor (Appgree).

Created AppHunt as a side project.

December 2010 – February 2013

Entrepreneur period. Startups and side projects with colleagues:

- Comaware: new technology based on **Machine Consciousness** to control virtual characters in video games and autonomous robots.
- Howmaths: Artificial Intelligence applied to math problems. An A* algorithms applied to solve math equation systems.
- A video game engine for Android developed from scratch as a side project to use Artificial Intelligence to control the non-player characters and procedural content generation.

September 2009 – January 2010

Visiting research at "Center for Computer Games Research" IT University of Copenhagen (Denmark), group of Artificial Intelligence in video games. Working in controlling characters in video games throw an eye tracking system and neural networks.

October 2007 – September 2011

Research staff in training at University Carlos III of Madrid. I supervised several bachelor's thesis.

Rated by the students as an exceptional teacher (2008).

December 2006 – August 2007 Sofware developer in Spain in several companies: GTD Ingeniería de Sistemas y Software; Secosol soluciones y domótica.

Research & Publications

- Several **papers** in international conferences and **book chapters** (see http://scholar.google.es/citations?hl=es&user=aHsYF-0AAAAJ for more details).
- Participation in scientific committee of international conferences (GECCO 2011, IADIS 2009).
- Complete list of publications publications: https://jorgemf.github.io/publications.html

Awards and prizes

Winner team of the **Human-Like Bot** contest.

Winner project (**Comaware**) in the **national contest** for **university entrepreneurs** organized by EOI. Awarded with an MBA at EOI and a study trip to Silicon Valley.

Winner team of the 5th contests of ideas for creating scientific and technological based companies of the University Carlos III of Madrid with the project **Comaware**. Six months of incubation in the business incubator of University Carlos III of Madrid.

Winner team of the **2K BotPrize 2010** international contest. The 2K BotPrize is an adaptation of the Turing test to video games. Monetary prize of a \$2,000 and a trip to 2K studios in Canberra, Australia.

Winner of the Car Set-up Optimization competition (using TORCS as simulator). \$500 prize.

2008 Rated by the students as an exceptional teacher, congratulated by the University Carlos III of Madrid

2006 Graduated with first-class honours and best bachelor's thesis, 2006.

2005 Scholarship for **outstanding academic achievement** in the course 2005-2006.

1999 and Finalist in the third edition of the national "**Spring Mathematics Contest**" held at the University Complutense of Madrid.

Media Appearances

October 2010 "Killer Bots Are Getting Human". John Bohannon. Science. Vol 330. no. 6000. pp. 30-

31. Science.

http://science.sciencemag.org/content/330/6000/30.2

October 2010 "The Awakening of Conscious Bots: Inside the Mind of the 2K BotPrize 2010 Winner",

aigamedev.com.

http://aigamedev.com/open/articles/conscious-bot/

September 2010 "Unreal Tournament 2010: Narrowing the Gap between Human and Bot". Surfdaddy

Orca. h+ magazine.

http://hplusmagazine.com/2010/09/10/unreal-tournament-2010-narrowing-gap-between-

human-and-bot/

September 2010 "Un equipo español queda en primer lugar del 2K BotPrize 2010" ("A Spanish team win

the 2K BotPrize 2010"). Lektu / Microsiervos. lainformacion.com

http://www.lainformacion.com/ciencia-y-tecnologia/tecnologia-general/un-equipo-espanol-queda-en-primer-lugar-del-2k-botprize-2010 eB2nYg5smd9hxIN2WnHWR1/

Talks

March 2011 Guest speaker in the VI Days of Imaginática 2011. University of Sevilla. "Conciencia

Artificial en Videojuegos: diseñando máquinas más humanas". ("Machine consciousness in video games: designing more human-like machines").

Idioms

Spanish Native

Advanced (6.3/10 Duolingo Profiency Exam, equivalent to 93/120 in TOELF, 6.8/9 in IELTS or C1 in CEFR) English